function getRandomNumber(max){
	var randomNumber = max * Math.random();
	randomNumber = parseInt(randomNumber);
	return randomNumber;
}

//1
function problem1501()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'arunmin': 65,
		'arunmax': 72,
		'bromin': 60,
		'bromax': 70,
		'mother': 68
		},
		{
		'arunmin': 60,
		'arunmax': 70,
		'bromin': 44,
		'bromax': 55,
		'mother': 65
		},
		{
		'arunmin': 70,
		'arunmax': 73,
		'bromin': 40,
		'bromax': 60,
		'mother': 67
		},
		{
		'arunmin': 55,
		'arunmax': 65,
		'bromin': 44,
		'bromax': 60,
		'mother': 57
		},
		{
		'arunmin': 50,
		'arunmax': 60,
		'bromin': 48,
		'bromax': 58,
		'mother': 54
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		arunmin= inputData[randomIndex]['arunmin'],
		arunmax= inputData[randomIndex]['arunmax'],
		bromin= inputData[randomIndex]['bromin'],
		bromax= inputData[randomIndex]['bromax'],
		mother=inputData[randomIndex]['mother'],
		probableweight,
		question = {};

	probableweight=(arunmin+arunmax+bromin+bromax+mother)/5;

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1501',
		'question': "In Arun's opinion, his weight is greater than"+arunmin+"kg but less than"+arunmax+"kg. His brother doest not agree with Arun and he thinks that Arun's weight is greater than"+bromin+"kg but less than"+bromax+"kg. His mother's view is that his weight cannot be greater than"+mother+"kg. If all are them are correct in their estimation, what is the average of different probable weights of Arun?",
		'options': {
			'A': probableweight,
			'B': probableweight - parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': probableweight + parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': probableweight - parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'A',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//2


function problem1502()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'person1': 16,
		'avgone': 50.25,
		'person2': 8,
		'avgtwo': 45.15
		},
		{
		'person1': 17,
		'avgone': 51.25,
		'person2': 9,
		'avgtwo': 46.15
		},
		{
		'person1': 18,
		'avgone': 52.25,
		'person2': 7,
		'avgtwo': 44.15
		},
		{
		'person1': 10,
		'avgone': 62.5,
		'person2': 6,
		'avgtwo': 33.33
		},
		{
		'person1': 12,
		'avgone': 55.3,
		'person2': 8,
		'avgtwo': 44.35
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		person1= inputData[randomIndex]['person1'],
		avgone= inputData[randomIndex]['avgone'],
		person2= inputData[randomIndex]['person2'],
		avgtwo= inputData[randomIndex]['avgtwo'],
		avg,
		question = {};

	avg=(person1*avgone+person2*avgtwo)/(person1+person2);
	avg=parseFloat(avg);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1502',
		'question': "The average weight of"+person1+"boys in a class is"+avgone+"kg and that of the remaining"+person2+"boys is"+avgtwo+"kg. Find the average weights of all the boys in the class.",
		'options': {
			'A': avg - parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': avg,
			'C': avg + parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': avg - parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'B',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//3
function problem1503()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'hmp': 8,
		'ootw': 65,
		'ia': 2.5
		},
		{
		'hmp': 10,
		'ootw': 72,
		'ia': 3
		},
		{
		'hmp': 12,
		'ootw': 63,
		'ia': 2
		},
		{
		'hmp': 18,
		'ootw': 60,
		'ia': 1
		},
		{
		'hmp': 11,
		'ootw': 69,
		'ia': 2
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		hmp= inputData[randomIndex]['hmp'],
		ootw= inputData[randomIndex]['ootw'],
		ia= inputData[randomIndex]['ia'],
		npw,
		question = {};

	hmp=parseInt(hmp);
	ootw=parseInt(ootw);
	ia=parseFloat(ia);
	npw=(hmp*ia)+ootw;

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1503',
		'question': "The average weight of"+hmp+"person's increases by"+ia+"kg when a new person comes in place of one of them weighing"+ootw+"kg. What might be the weight of the new person?",
		'options': {
			'A': npw+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': npw - parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': npw,
			'D': npw - parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'C',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}



//4
function problem1504()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'noo': 10,
		'avg': 3.2,
		'rnoo': 40,
		'trun': 282
		},
		{
		'noo': 12,
		'avg': 4.2,
		'rnoo': 50,
		'trun': 322
		},
		{
		'noo': 11,
		'avg': 3.2,
		'rnoo': 39,
		'trun': 275
		},
		{
		'noo': 11,
		'avg': 4.5,
		'rnoo': 30,
		'trun': 240
		},
		{
		'noo': 9,
		'avg': 2.2,
		'rnoo': 30,
		'trun': 252
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		noo= inputData[randomIndex]['noo'],
		avg= inputData[randomIndex]['avg'],
		rnoo= inputData[randomIndex]['rnoo'],
		trun= inputData[randomIndex]['trun'],
		nrr,
		question = {};

	nrr=(trun-(avg*noo))/rnoo;

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1504',
		'question': "In the first"+noo+"overs of a cricket game, the run rate was only"+avg+"What should be the run rate in the remaining"+rnoo+"overs to reach the target of"+trun+"runs?",
		'options': {
			'A': nrr+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': nrr- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': nrr- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': nrr 
		},
		'answer': 'D',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}



//5
function problem1505()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'ngp': 2,
		'np': 2,
		'ngc': 3,
		'aagp': 67,
		'aap': 35,
		'aagc': 6
		},
		{
		'ngp': 2,
		'np': 2,
		'ngc': 4,
		'aagp': 65,
		'aap': 40,
		'aagc': 8
		},
		{
		'ngp': 2,
		'np': 2,
		'ngc': 3,
		'aagp': 60,
		'aap': 42,
		'aagc': 8
		},
		{
		'ngp': 2,
		'np': 2,
		'ngc': 3,
		'aagp': 55,
		'aap': 50,
		'aagc': 5
		},
		{
		'ngp': 2,
		'np': 2,
		'ngc': 3,
		'aagp': 76,
		'aap': 53,
		'aagc': 12
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		ngp= inputData[randomIndex]['ngp'],
		np= inputData[randomIndex]['np'],
		ngc= inputData[randomIndex]['ngc'],
		aagp= inputData[randomIndex]['aagp'],
		aap= inputData[randomIndex]['aap'],
		aagc= inputData[randomIndex]['aagc'],
		af,
		question = {};

	ngp=parseFloat(ngp);
	np=parseFloat(np);
	ngc=parseFloat(ngc);
	aagp=parseFloat(aagp);
	aap=parseFloat(aap);
	aagc=parseFloat(aagc);
	af=(aagp*ngp+np*aap+ngc*aagc)/(ngp+np+ngc);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1505',
		'question': "A family consists of"+ngp+"grandparents,"+np+"parents and "+ngc+"grandchildren. The average age of the grandparents is"+aagp+"years, that of the parents is "+aap+" years and that of the grandchildren is "+aagc+" years. What is the average age of the family?",
		'options': {
			'A': af,
			'B': af- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': af- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': af+ parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'A',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//6
function problem1506()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'apq': 5050,
		'aqr': 6250,
		'apr': 5200
		},
		{
		'apq': 5070,
		'aqr': 6270,
		'apr': 5220
		},
		{
		'apq': 5060,
		'aqr': 6260,
		'apr': 5210
		},
		{
		'apq': 5030,
		'aqr': 6280,
		'apr': 5220
		},
		{
		'apq': 5080,
		'aqr': 6270,
		'apr': 5220
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		apq= inputData[randomIndex]['apq'],
		aqr= inputData[randomIndex]['aqr'],
		apr= inputData[randomIndex]['apr'],
		p,
		question = {};

	p=((apq*2+aqr*2+apr*2)/2)-(aqr*2);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1506',
		'question': "The average monthly income of P and Q is Rs. "+apq+". The average monthly income of Q and R is Rs. "+aqr+" and the average monthly income of P and R is Rs. "+apr+". The monthly income of P is:",
		'options': {
			'A': p- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': p,
			'C': p- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': p+ parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'B',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//7
function problem1507()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'abc': 45,
		'ab': 40,
		'bc': 43
		},
		{
		'abc': 50,
		'ab': 45,
		'bc': 40
		},
		{
		'abc': 55,
		'ab': 45,
		'bc': 53
		},
		{
		'abc': 45,
		'ab': 40,
		'bc': 43
		},
		{
		'abc': 45,
		'ab': 48,
		'bc': 33
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		abc= inputData[randomIndex]['abc'],
		ab= inputData[randomIndex]['ab'],
		bc= inputData[randomIndex]['bc'],
		b,
		question = {};

	abc=parseInt(abc);
	ab=parseInt(ab);
	bc=parseInt(bc);
	b=2*bc-(3*abc-2*ab);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1507',
		'question': "The average weight of A, B and C is "+abc+" kg. If the average weight of A and B be "+ab+" kg and that of B and C be "+bc+" kg, then the weight of B is:",
		'options': {
			'A': b- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': b- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': b,
			'D': b+ parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'C',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//8
function problem1508()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'ahwc': 27,
		'ybahwc': 3,
		'awc': 20,
		'ybawc': 5
		},
		{
		'ahwc': 37,
		'ybahwc': 3,
		'awc': 25,
		'ybawc': 5
		},
		{
		'ahwc': 27,
		'ybahwc': 4,
		'awc': 20,
		'ybawc': 6
		},
		{
		'ahwc': 28,
		'ybahwc': 4,
		'awc': 24,
		'ybawc': 6
		},
		{
		'ahwc': 23,
		'ybahwc': 2,
		'awc': 21,
		'ybawc': 4
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		ahwc= inputData[randomIndex]['ahwc'],
		ybahwc= inputData[randomIndex]['ybahwc'],
		awc= inputData[randomIndex]['awc'],
		ybawc= inputData[randomIndex]['ybawc'],
		h,
		question = {};

	ahwc=parseInt(ahwc);
	ybahwc=parseInt(ybahwc);
	awc=parseInt(awc);
	ybawc=parseInt(ybawc);
	h=(ahwc*3+3*(ybahwc))-(awc*2+2*(ybawc));

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1508',
		'question': "The average age of husband, wife and their child "+ybahwc+" years ago was "+ahwc+" years and that of wife and the child "+ybawc+" years ago was "+awc+" years. The present age of the husband is:",
		'options': {
			'A': h- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': h- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': h+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': h
		},
		'answer': 'D',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}



//9
function problem1509()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'student1': 55,
		'student2': 60,
		'student3': 45,
		'mark1': 50,
		'mark2': 55,
		'mark3': 60
		},
		{
		'student1': 56,
		'student2': 62,
		'student3': 47,
		'mark1': 52,
		'mark2': 54,
		'mark3': 69
		},
		{
		'student1': 54,
		'student2': 66,
		'student3': 42,
		'mark1': 51,
		'mark2': 52,
		'mark3': 69
		},
		{
		'student1': 55,
		'student2': 60,
		'student3': 45,
		'mark1': 50,
		'mark2': 55,
		'mark3': 60
		},
		{
		'student1': 65,
		'student2': 70,
		'student3': 55,
		'mark1': 40,
		'mark2': 45,
		'mark3': 50
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		student1= inputData[randomIndex]['student1'],
		student2= inputData[randomIndex]['student2'],
		student3= inputData[randomIndex]['student3'],
		mark1= inputData[randomIndex]['mark1'],
		mark2= inputData[randomIndex]['mark2'],
		mark3= inputData[randomIndex]['mark3'],
		avg,
		question = {};

	avg=(student1*mark1+student2*mark2+student3*mark3)/(student1+student2+student3);
	avg=parseFloat(avg);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1509',
		'question': "If the average marks of three batches of "+student1+", "+student2+" and "+student3+" students respectively is "+mark1+", "+mark2+", "+mark3+", then the average marks of all the students is:",
		'options': {
			'A': avg,
			'B': avg- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': avg+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': avg- parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'A',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//10
function problem1510()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'crt': 63,
		'wrong': 83,
		'avgincreased': .5
		},
		{
		'crt': 62,
		'wrong': 82,
		'avgincreased': .5
		},
		{
		'crt': 61,
		'wrong': 81,
		'avgincreased': .5
		},
		{
		'crt': 63,
		'wrong': 83,
		'avgincreased': 1
		},
		{
		'crt': 62,
		'wrong': 82,
		'avgincreased': 1
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		crt= inputData[randomIndex]['crt'],
		wrong= inputData[randomIndex]['wrong'],
		avgincreased= inputData[randomIndex]['avgincreased'],
		pupils,
		question = {};

	pupils=(crt-wrong)/avgincreased;
	if(pupils<0)
	{
		pupils=-1*pupils
	}
	pupils=parseFloat(pupils);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1510',
		'question': "A pupil's marks were wrongly entered as "+wrong+" instead of "+crt+". Due to that the average marks for the class got increased by "+avgincreased+". The number of pupils in the class is:",
		'options': {
			'A': pupils- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': pupils,
			'C': pupils+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': pupils- parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'B',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}



//11
function problem1511()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'total': 110,
		'boundaries': 3,
		'six': 8
		},
		{
		'total': 100,
		'boundaries': 3,
		'six': 8
		},
		{
		'total': 110,
		'boundaries': 4,
		'six': 8
		},
		{
		'total': 120,
		'boundaries': 3,
		'six': 8
		},
		{
		'total': 110,
		'boundaries': 2,
		'six': 7
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		total= inputData[randomIndex]['total'],
		boundaries= inputData[randomIndex]['boundaries'],
		six= inputData[randomIndex]['six'],
		percentage,
		question = {};

	percentage=(total-(boundaries*4+six*6))*100/total;
	percentage=parseFloat(percentage);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1511',
		'question': "A batsman scored "+total+" runs which included "+boundaries+" boundaries and "+six+" sixes. What percent of his total score did he make by running between the wickets?",
		'options': {
			'A': percentage- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': percentage+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': percentage,
			'D': percentage- parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'C',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//12
function problem1512()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'sells': 40,
		'still': 420
		},
		{
		'sells': 50,
		'still': 440
		},
		{
		'sells': 30,
		'still': 400
		},
		{
		'sells': 20,
		'still': 300
		},
		{
		'sells': 30,
		'still': 410
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		sells= inputData[randomIndex]['sells'],
		still= inputData[randomIndex]['still'],
		hehad,
		question = {};

	hehad=(still*sells/100)+still;
	hehad=parseFloat(hehad);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1512',
		'question': "A fruit seller had some apples. He sells "+sells+"% apples and still has "+still+" apples. Originally, he had:",
		'options': {
			'A': hehad- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': hehad+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': hehad- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': hehad
		},
		'answer': 'D',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//13
function problem1513()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'one': 55,
		'invalid': 20,
		'total':7500
		},
		{
		'one': 57,
		'invalid': 20,
		'total':7000
		},
		{
		'one': 53,
		'invalid': 10,
		'total':7300
		},
		{
		'one': 55,
		'invalid': 30,
		'total':6500
		},
		{
		'one': 52,
		'invalid': 10,
		'total':6500
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		one= inputData[randomIndex]['one'],
		invalid= inputData[randomIndex]['invalid'],
		total= inputData[randomIndex]['total'],
		other,
		question = {};

	other=(total-(total*invalid/100))*(100-one)/100;

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1513',
		'question': "In an election between two candidates, one got "+one+"% of the total valid votes, "+invalid+"% of the votes were invalid. If the total number of votes was "+total+", the number of valid votes that the other candidate got, was:",
		'options': {
			'A': other,
			'B': other+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': other- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': other- parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'A',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//14
function problem1514()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'candidate1': 1135,
		'candidate2': 7636,
		'candidate3':11628
		},
		{
		'candidate1': 1145,
		'candidate2': 7646,
		'candidate3':11648
		},
		{
		'candidate1': 1155,
		'candidate2': 7656,
		'candidate3':11658
		},
		{
		'candidate1': 1165,
		'candidate2': 7666,
		'candidate3':11668
		},
		{
		'candidate1': 1125,
		'candidate2': 7626,
		'candidate3':11618
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		candidate1= inputData[randomIndex]['candidate1'],
		candidate2= inputData[randomIndex]['candidate2'],
		candidate3= inputData[randomIndex]['candidate3'],
		percentage=parseFloat(),
		question = {};

	if(candidate1>candidate2)
	{
		if(candidate1>candidate3)
		{
			percentage=candidate1*100/(candidate1+candidate2+candidate3);
		}
	}
	if(candidate2>candidate1)
	{
		if(candidate2>candidate3)
		{
			percentage=candidate2*100/(candidate1+candidate2+candidate3);
		}
	}

	if(candidate3>candidate1)
	{
		if(candidate3>candidate2)
		{
			percentage=candidate3*100/(candidate1+candidate2+candidate3);
		}
	}

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1514',
		'question': "Three candidates contested an election and received "+candidate1+", "+candidate2+" and "+candidate3+" votes respectively. What percentage of the total votes did the winning candidate get?",
		'options': {
			'A': percentage+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': percentage,
			'C': percentage- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': percentage- parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'B',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}



//15
function problem1515()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'buys': 66500,
		'rebate': 6,
		'salestax':10
		},
		{
		'buys': 66400,
		'rebate': 7,
		'salestax':8
		},
		{
		'buys': 66200,
		'rebate': 6,
		'salestax':9
		},
		{
		'buys': 66100,
		'rebate': 9,
		'salestax':12
		},
		{
		'buys': 66300,
		'rebate': 5,
		'salestax':15
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		buys= inputData[randomIndex]['buys'],
		rebate= inputData[randomIndex]['rebate'],
		salestax= inputData[randomIndex]['salestax'],
		payamout=parseFloat(),
		question = {};

	payamout=(buys-(buys*rebate/100))+((buys-(buys*rebate/100))*salestax/100);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1515',
		'question': "Rajeev buys good worth Rs. "+buys+". He gets a rebate of "+rebate+"% on it. After getting the rebate, he pays sales tax @ "+salestax+"%. Find the amount he will have to pay for the goods.",
		'options': {
			'A': payamout+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': payamout- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': payamout,
			'D': payamout- parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'C',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//16
function problem1516()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'buys': 4700,
		'repairs': 800,
		'sells':5800
		},
		{
		'buys': 4700,
		'repairs': 700,
		'sells':5700
		},
		{
		'buys': 4800,
		'repairs': 900,
		'sells':5900
		},
		{
		'buys': 4500,
		'repairs': 600,
		'sells':5600
		},
		{
		'buys': 4400,
		'repairs': 400,
		'sells':5400
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		buys= inputData[randomIndex]['buys'],
		repairs= inputData[randomIndex]['repairs'],
		sells= inputData[randomIndex]['sells'],
		gainper,
		question = {};

	gainper=(sells-(buys+repairs))*100/(buys+repairs);
	gainper=parseFloat(gainper);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1516',
		'question': "Alfred buys an old scooter for Rs. "+buys+" and spends Rs. "+repairs+" on its repairs. If he sells the scooter for Rs. "+sells+", his gain percent is:",
		'options': {
			'A': gainper+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': gainper- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': gainper- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': gainper
		},
		'answer': 'D',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//17
function problem1517()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'buys': 1400,
		'sellingloss': 15
		},
		{
		'buys': 1500,
		'sellingloss': 16
		},
		{
		'buys': 1200,
		'sellingloss': 12
		},
		{
		'buys': 1000,
		'sellingloss': 10
		},
		{
		'buys': 1100,
		'sellingloss': 11
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		buys= inputData[randomIndex]['buys'],
		sellingloss= inputData[randomIndex]['sellingloss'],
		sellingprice=parseFloat(),
		question = {};

	sellingprice=buys-(buys*sellingloss/100);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1517',
		'question': "A man buys a cycle for Rs. "+buys+" and sells it at a loss of "+sellingloss+"%. What is the selling price of the cycle?",
		'options': {
			'A': sellingprice,
			'B': sellingprice- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': sellingprice- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': sellingprice+ parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'A',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//18
function problem1518()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'sold': 2500,
		'cost': 2000
		},
		{
		'sold': 3000,
		'cost': 2500
		},
		{
		'sold': 2000,
		'cost': 1500
		},
		{
		'sold': 4000,
		'cost': 3000
		},
		{
		'sold': 4500,
		'cost': 3500
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		sold= inputData[randomIndex]['sold'],
		cost= inputData[randomIndex]['cost'],
		profitper=parseFloat(),
		question = {};

	profitper=(sold-cost)*100/cost;

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1518',
		'question': "A shopkeeper sold an article for Rs. "+sold+". If the cost price of the article is "+cost+", find the profit percent.",
		'options': {
			'A': profitper- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': profitper,
			'C': profitper- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': profitper+ parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'B',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}


//19
function problem1519()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'purchase': 8000,
		'sellingloss': 10
		},
		{
		'purchase': 6000,
		'sellingloss': 8
		},
		{
		'purchase': 7000,
		'sellingloss': 10
		},
		{
		'purchase': 6000,
		'sellingloss': 8
		},
		{
		'purchase': 9000,
		'sellingloss': 15
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		purchase= inputData[randomIndex]['purchase'],
		sellingloss= inputData[randomIndex]['sellingloss'],
		selprice=parseFloat(),
		question = {};

	selprice=purchase-(purchase*sellingloss/100);

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1519',
		'question': "A man purchases a TV for Rs. "+purchase+" and sells it at "+sellingloss+"% loss. What is the selling price of T.V?",
		'options': {
			'A': selprice- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': selprice- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': selprice,
			'D': selprice+ parseInt(Math.random()*10)
		},
		'answer': 'C',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}



//20
function problem1520()
{
	var inputData = [{
		'purchase': 1540,
		'profitpercentage': 25
		},
		{
		'purchase': 1550,
		'profitpercentage': 27
		},
		{
		'purchase': 1560,
		'profitpercentage': 29
		},
		{
		'purchase': 1580,
		'profitpercentage': 30
		},
		{
		'purchase': 1500,
		'profitpercentage': 20
		}],
		randomIndex = getRandomNumber(inputData.length),
		purchase= inputData[randomIndex]['purchase'],
		profitpercentage= inputData[randomIndex]['profitpercentage'],
		selprice=parseFloat(),
		question = {};

	selprice=(purchase*profitpercentage/100)+purchase;

	question = {
		'type': 'single',
		'id': '1520',
		'question': "Ramesh bought a chair for Rs. "+purchase+" and sold it to Suresh. If Ramesh earned a profit of "+profitpercentage+"%, find the selling price of chair.",
		'options': {
			'A': selprice- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'B': selprice- parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'C': selprice+ parseInt(Math.random()*10),
			'D': selprice
		},
		'answer': 'D',
		'author-id': '15'
	}
	
	return question;
	
}